<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Afghanistan Cricket Team &#8211; Future Health Oregonstate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/tag/afghanistan-cricket-team/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 15:32:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/the.png</url>
	<title>Afghanistan Cricket Team &#8211; Future Health Oregonstate</title>
	<link>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Maxwell disproved the notion of &#8216;winning the match alone&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-disproved-the-notion-of-winning-the-match-alone/</link>
					<comments>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-disproved-the-notion-of-winning-the-match-alone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[administrator]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 15:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan Cricket Team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia cricket team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glenn Maxwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wasim Akram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Cup Cricket 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Seeing the innings, one thing can be said &#8211; incredible! Some may say superhuman. The real thing is that Glenn Maxwell&#8217;s batting yesterday, the eyes of the cricket lovers are dazzled. It is possible to win the match in this way! Australia lost 7 wickets for 91 runs chasing Afghanistan&#8217;s 291 runs at the Wankhede ... <a title="Maxwell disproved the notion of &#8216;winning the match alone&#8217;" class="read-more" href="https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-disproved-the-notion-of-winning-the-match-alone/" aria-label="More on Maxwell disproved the notion of &#8216;winning the match alone&#8217;">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Seeing the innings, one thing can be said &#8211; incredible! Some may say superhuman. The real thing is that Glenn Maxwell&#8217;s batting yesterday, the eyes of the cricket lovers are dazzled. It is possible to win the match in this way!</p>



<p>Australia lost 7 wickets for 91 runs chasing Afghanistan&#8217;s 291 runs at the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai. Many people were watching Pat Cummins&#8217; team lose. But Glenn Maxwell and captain Cummins made an unbroken 202-run partnership of 170 balls to give Australia an incredible victory.</p>



<p>Maxwell played an unbeaten innings of 201 runs from 128 balls despite leg cramps. It is considered by many to be the best innings in ODI history. Pakistan legend Wasim Akram, however, did not talk about these. As cricket is a team game, Akram reminded us of an adage &#8211; &#8216;One cannot win a match alone.&#8217; According to Akram, Maxwell disproved the claim.</p>



<p>Maxwell lay down several times in the middle of batting due to leg cramps. Physio went to the field and wanted to bring him out. But Maxwell, desperate to win the team, did not accept it. After him there was no more batsman, Australia was also far away from victory. Maxwell-Cummins did not take several singles in such a situation. The Australian captain had full confidence in Maxwell. Knew, if anyone can win this match, Maxwell can do it. That&#8217;s exactly what happened in the end.</p>



<p>Akram told Pakistani TV channel &#8216;A Sports&#8217;, &#8216;Unbelievable. It&#8217;s a one man show. Legendary batting. There is a saying, one can never win a match. But now it is completely false. Maxwell has shown that it is possible to win the team alone.</p>



<p>Appreciating Maxwell&#8217;s willpower, Akram said, &#8216;(To play such an innings) requires willpower and Maxwell has shown that. She was suffering from cramps. Cricketers know how much it hurts. But did not give up and fought.&#8217; The left-arm fast bowler also praised Australian captain Pat Cummins&#8217; 68-ball unbeaten innings of 12 runs, &#8216;Pat Cummins also needs to be applauded. Understanding the situation, he gave strike to Maxwell.</p>



<p>Wasim Akram said that he has never seen such a fighting innings, &#8216;Maxwell has shown by scoring 201 runs, he is now the best ODI player. I have played cricket for almost 20 years and have been working on this game since then. But I have never seen such a fighting innings.&#8217;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-disproved-the-notion-of-winning-the-match-alone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
