<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Future Health Oregonstate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 15:33:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/the.png</url>
	<title>News &#8211; Future Health Oregonstate</title>
	<link>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Health emergency declared in 3 districts of Pakistan including Lahore due to air pollution</title>
		<link>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/health-emergency-declared-in-3-districts-of-pakistan-including-lahore-due-to-air-pollution/</link>
					<comments>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/health-emergency-declared-in-3-districts-of-pakistan-including-lahore-due-to-air-pollution/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[administrator]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 15:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pakistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the environment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The caretaker government of Pakistan&#8217;s Punjab province has declared an &#8216;environmental and health emergency&#8217; in three districts including Lahore due to air pollution. This situation will continue for four days from tomorrow Thursday to Sunday to reduce pollution. A holiday has been declared in those three districts for four days. Dawn&#8217;s news. According to the ... <a title="Health emergency declared in 3 districts of Pakistan including Lahore due to air pollution" class="read-more" href="https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/health-emergency-declared-in-3-districts-of-pakistan-including-lahore-due-to-air-pollution/" aria-label="More on Health emergency declared in 3 districts of Pakistan including Lahore due to air pollution">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The caretaker government of Pakistan&#8217;s Punjab province has declared an &#8216;environmental and health emergency&#8217; in three districts including Lahore due to air pollution. This situation will continue for four days from tomorrow Thursday to Sunday to reduce pollution. A holiday has been declared in those three districts for four days. Dawn&#8217;s news.</p>



<p>According to the announcement given by the provincial government, all the markets, shopping malls, restaurants, cinema halls, gymnasiums, schools and government and private offices of the three districts will be closed on those four days. Apart from Lahore, the announcement will be effective in Gojranwala and Hafizabad districts. Movement of government and private vehicles will also be limited in these three districts.</p>



<p>According to the government notification, drug shops, petrol pumps, bakeries, grocery stores, dairy shops, vegetable and meat shops will remain open.</p>



<p>The caretaker chief minister of the province, Mohsin Naqvi, said that Section 144 has been imposed in these three districts. He said that next Thursday and Friday, public holidays have been announced in those three districts. And Saturday and Sunday are weekends.</p>



<p>The Chief Minister said that the government will not close the factories. Pollution needs to be stopped in Lahore. The city environment needs rest.</p>



<p>Mohsin Naqvi said, &#8216;Children and elderly people are suffering from asthma and eye diseases.&#8217;</p>



<p>Switzerland-based organization regularly highlights the air pollution situation of the world&#8217;s cities. This live or instant AQI index is based on air quality and informs and alerts people about how clean or polluted the air is in a particular city.</p>



<p>According to IQAir data, Lahore has been at the top of the world for air pollution for almost two weeks. Today, Monday, the city is at the top position. The city has a score of 455.</p>



<p>According to the IQAir criteria, a score of 51 to 100 is considered &#8216;moderate&#8217; or &#8216;acceptable&#8217; air quality. A score of 101 to 150 is considered &#8216;unhealthy for sensitive groups&#8217;. People in sensitive groups are most at risk when air pollution is high. Among them are the elderly, children, pregnant women, people suffering from complex diseases. Experts advise that special care should be taken about them.</p>



<p>A score of 151 to 200 is &#8216;unhealthy&#8217; air. A score of 201 to 300 is considered &#8216;very unhealthy&#8217; air. A score of 301 and above is considered &#8216;disastrous&#8217; or &#8216;risky&#8217;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/health-emergency-declared-in-3-districts-of-pakistan-including-lahore-due-to-air-pollution/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maxwell disproved the notion of &#8216;winning the match alone&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-disproved-the-notion-of-winning-the-match-alone/</link>
					<comments>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-disproved-the-notion-of-winning-the-match-alone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[administrator]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 15:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan Cricket Team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia cricket team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glenn Maxwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wasim Akram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Cup Cricket 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Seeing the innings, one thing can be said &#8211; incredible! Some may say superhuman. The real thing is that Glenn Maxwell&#8217;s batting yesterday, the eyes of the cricket lovers are dazzled. It is possible to win the match in this way! Australia lost 7 wickets for 91 runs chasing Afghanistan&#8217;s 291 runs at the Wankhede ... <a title="Maxwell disproved the notion of &#8216;winning the match alone&#8217;" class="read-more" href="https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-disproved-the-notion-of-winning-the-match-alone/" aria-label="More on Maxwell disproved the notion of &#8216;winning the match alone&#8217;">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Seeing the innings, one thing can be said &#8211; incredible! Some may say superhuman. The real thing is that Glenn Maxwell&#8217;s batting yesterday, the eyes of the cricket lovers are dazzled. It is possible to win the match in this way!</p>



<p>Australia lost 7 wickets for 91 runs chasing Afghanistan&#8217;s 291 runs at the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai. Many people were watching Pat Cummins&#8217; team lose. But Glenn Maxwell and captain Cummins made an unbroken 202-run partnership of 170 balls to give Australia an incredible victory.</p>



<p>Maxwell played an unbeaten innings of 201 runs from 128 balls despite leg cramps. It is considered by many to be the best innings in ODI history. Pakistan legend Wasim Akram, however, did not talk about these. As cricket is a team game, Akram reminded us of an adage &#8211; &#8216;One cannot win a match alone.&#8217; According to Akram, Maxwell disproved the claim.</p>



<p>Maxwell lay down several times in the middle of batting due to leg cramps. Physio went to the field and wanted to bring him out. But Maxwell, desperate to win the team, did not accept it. After him there was no more batsman, Australia was also far away from victory. Maxwell-Cummins did not take several singles in such a situation. The Australian captain had full confidence in Maxwell. Knew, if anyone can win this match, Maxwell can do it. That&#8217;s exactly what happened in the end.</p>



<p>Akram told Pakistani TV channel &#8216;A Sports&#8217;, &#8216;Unbelievable. It&#8217;s a one man show. Legendary batting. There is a saying, one can never win a match. But now it is completely false. Maxwell has shown that it is possible to win the team alone.</p>



<p>Appreciating Maxwell&#8217;s willpower, Akram said, &#8216;(To play such an innings) requires willpower and Maxwell has shown that. She was suffering from cramps. Cricketers know how much it hurts. But did not give up and fought.&#8217; The left-arm fast bowler also praised Australian captain Pat Cummins&#8217; 68-ball unbeaten innings of 12 runs, &#8216;Pat Cummins also needs to be applauded. Understanding the situation, he gave strike to Maxwell.</p>



<p>Wasim Akram said that he has never seen such a fighting innings, &#8216;Maxwell has shown by scoring 201 runs, he is now the best ODI player. I have played cricket for almost 20 years and have been working on this game since then. But I have never seen such a fighting innings.&#8217;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-disproved-the-notion-of-winning-the-match-alone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maxwell 201*: Is this the best innings in ODI history?</title>
		<link>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-201-is-this-the-best-innings-in-odi-history/</link>
					<comments>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-201-is-this-the-best-innings-in-odi-history/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[administrator]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 15:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arvind de Silva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben Stokes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herschel Gibbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Cup Cricket 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Incredible, unprecedented, unimaginable, unimaginable, incomparable, superhuman—what other adjectives can characterize Glenn Maxwell&#8217;s unbeaten innings of 201? The world of cricket has seen an innings that touched two centuries in ODI history 10 times before. One Rohit Sharma did thrice. However, Rohit and the rest made double centuries before batting. The only exception is Maxwell. At ... <a title="Maxwell 201*: Is this the best innings in ODI history?" class="read-more" href="https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-201-is-this-the-best-innings-in-odi-history/" aria-label="More on Maxwell 201*: Is this the best innings in ODI history?">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Incredible, unprecedented, unimaginable, unimaginable, incomparable, superhuman—what other adjectives can characterize Glenn Maxwell&#8217;s unbeaten innings of 201?</p>



<p>The world of cricket has seen an innings that touched two centuries in ODI history 10 times before. One Rohit Sharma did thrice. However, Rohit and the rest made double centuries before batting. The only exception is Maxwell. At the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai, with the wind from the Arabian Sea blowing in Australia&#8217;s favour, cricket&#8217;s &#8216;Big Show&#8217; arrived at 22 yards. 49 runs for the loss of 4 wickets in 8.2 overs; Afghanistan&#8217;s two pacers Naveen Ul Haq and Azmatullah Omarzai bowled Australia at that time.</p>



<p>Then Marnus Labuchen&#8217;s run-out and Rashid Khan&#8217;s bowling made the score 49 for 4 and 91 for 7. If anyone had said, &#8216;But Australia will win by 292 runs&#8217;, not many people would have believed that! But Maxwell proved everyone wrong by standing on one leg in the rubble under the pressure. Captain Pat Cummins accompanied him as the hero behind the scenes. Without losing any wicket, Australia reached the desired goal, reached the semi-finals of the World Cup. The run chase that Australia won, &#8216;Half fit&#8217; Maxwell alone contributed 68.60%!</p>



<p>Maxwell&#8217;s lifetime innings is considered by many to be the best ever innings in ODIs. In the eyes of Sachin Tendulkar, whose hand saw the first ODI double century in the world of cricket, this is the best innings he has seen in his life. After Maxwell&#8217;s heroics, the ICC itself, the BBC and the Daily Mail analyzed some of the epic innings in ODI history to find some of the best. This arrangement is about the selected innings-</p>



<p><strong>Ben Stokes, England:</strong></p>



<p><strong>2019 World Cup final, opponent New Zealand</strong></p>



<p><strong>84* runs off 98 balls</strong></p>



<p>Four years ago he scored an unbeaten 84 off 98 balls in the &#8216;Barest of All Margins&#8217; final at Lord&#8217;s. Because of that innings, the match was made into a super over. Later, England won the ODI World Cup for the first time in terms of scoring more boundaries. The innings played against formidable opposition like New Zealand on cricket&#8217;s biggest stage is considered one of the greatest ever.</p>



<p><strong>Glenn Maxwell, Australia:</strong></p>



<p><strong>2023 World Cup first round, opponent Netherlands</strong></p>



<p><strong>106 runs off 44 balls</strong></p>



<p>Glenn Maxwell&#8217;s innings, played just two weeks ago, also made it to the top 10. He had no fifty in the last 10 innings prior to this innings. It has come under a lot of criticism. But Maxwell wanted to answer everything with the bat. The century was the fastest in World Cup history as the Netherlands bowled the bowlers through the innings.</p>



<p><strong>Herschel Gibbs, South Africa:</strong></p>



<p><strong>2006 bilateral series, against Australia</strong></p>



<p><strong>175 runs off 111 balls</strong></p>



<p>The idea that a team would score 400 runs in an ODI, does not seem to have occurred to many in those days. But Australia made history that day in Johannesburg. Scored 434 runs in 50 overs. South Africa made a unique achievement that day on top of the Everest; Herschel Gibbs is the hero of the epic. This South African batsman gave a superhuman innings of 175 runs off 111 balls. Due to his innings, the Proteas won the match as well as the series. 438 runs for the loss of 9 wickets is still the highest successful run chase in the history of cricket.</p>



<p><strong>AB de Villiers, South Africa:</strong></p>



<p><strong>2015 bilateral series, opponent West Indies</strong></p>



<p><strong>149 runs off 44 balls</strong></p>



<p>AB de Villiers took himself to unique heights with this innings that changed the definition of batting in the modern era. He completed the 31-ball century, which is the fastest in the history of ODIs, after unleashing a deluge on the West Indies bowlers. How he played such an innings, the story is told by &#8216;Mr. 360 degrees&#8217;. &#8216;The opportunity was looking for me. I was very hot in the dressing room. I had already decided, this is how I will play. Perhaps being aggressive was the main reason. I wanted to play from the first ball,&#8221; said de Villiers.</p>



<p><strong>Kapil Dev, India:</strong></p>



<p><strong>1983 World Cup group stage, opponent Zimbabwe</strong></p>



<p><strong>175* runs off 138 balls</strong></p>



<p>If you want to survive in the World Cup, you have to win, India does not have 5 wickets to score 17 runs in such a match against Zimbabwe! From there, captain Kapil Dev took the team to 266 runs. Kapil&#8217;s single run of 175! Prior to Maxwell&#8217;s innings yesterday, this was the individual highest for a batsman to hit six or later in ODIs. In those days bats were not so modern, boundaries were not so small as they are now. In consideration of these 175 must be equal to the current 235! There were three more World Cup matches on that day 38 years ago. And at that time not all matches were telecasted.</p>



<p>It was one of those matches that was not televised. Not even a video footage of Kapil&#8217;s epic innings is available. However, before seeing Maxwell&#8217;s innings yesterday, his innings was considered by most cricket-buddhas to be the best one-day innings ever. Kapil was once asked if he regretted not having a video of his innings. In response, Kapil said, &#8216;Some events are better heard than seen.&#8217; He also said, after that innings, the confidence was born that the Indian team can turn around from any situation and defeat any team. In the end, it was Kapil-led India that created a stir by winning the &#8217;83 World Cup.</p>



<p><strong>Glenn Maxwell, Australia:</strong></p>



<p><strong>2023 World Cup first round, opponent Afghanistan</strong></p>



<p><strong>201* runs off 128 balls</strong></p>



<p>The story of this innings has been told at the beginning. Discussions can only be about getting recognition for excellence. Some may question Maxwell&#8217;s superiority there. You can say &#8211; the opponents Afghanistan are not like superpowers, the boundaries of the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai are very small, Maxwell has got &#8216;life&#8217; more than once, the match was not life-or-death for Australia or even if they lose tomorrow, they would have reached the semi-finals. But when you imagine the &#8216;half-fit&#8217; Maxwell&#8217;s indomitable spirit, or remember the moments when he collapsed on the field in pain and stood up again to fight for the country, there is no way to put Maxwell above everything!</p>



<p><strong>Viv Richards, West Indies:</strong></p>



<p><strong>1984 bilateral series, against England</strong></p>



<p><strong>189* runs off 170 balls</strong></p>



<p>This was the personal highest in ODIs until 1997. At Old Trafford, Viv Richards is standing as a wall on one side, while wickets are falling on the other side. This procession of coming and going teammates finally stopped in a wonderful pairing with Michael Holding. When West Indies lost 9 wickets for 166 runs, Richards was unbeaten on 96 runs. From there he scored another 106 runs in the unbroken last wicket partnership with Holding. The innings of the Caribbean reached 272 for 9 wickets. Viv 189 runs unbeaten. England couldn&#8217;t even make Vive&#8217;s run chasing the target. All out was 168 runs.</p>



<p><strong>Arvind de Silva, Sri Lanka:</strong></p>



<p><strong>1996 World Cup final, opponent Australia</strong></p>



<p><strong>107* runs off 124 balls</strong></p>



<p>The story of Sri Lanka winning the World Cup in 1996 is like a fairy tale. The hero of the fairy tale is Arvind de Silva. Chasing 242 in the final in Lahore, Sri Lanka lost 2 for 23 in front of Australia&#8217;s bowling attack of Glenn McGrath-Shane Warne. De Silva managed the disaster by forming a partnership of 125 runs with Asanka Gurusingh. Although Gurusinghe was dismissed for a personal 65 runs, he left the field after finishing the match with captain Arjuna Ranatunga. Remains unbeaten on 107 runs. In the final, he was the man of the match, before that, De Silva won the best player award in the semi-final. He is the only player to be man of the match in the semi-final and final of a World Cup so far.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://future.health.oregonstate.edu/maxwell-201-is-this-the-best-innings-in-odi-history/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
